betfair.com 2017-12-29

# Betfair

### _1\. INTRODUCTION_

This Privacy & Cookie Policy (the “Policy”) sets out the basis on which any personal information we collect from you or that you provide to us will be processed by us. Paddy Power Betfair plc have created this Policy in order to demonstrate our commitment to preserving the privacy of all visitors to our websites and customers of our services. We are committed to ensuring that all services and activities made available through our websites are provided in a safe and secure environment.

For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998, the Paddy Power data controller is Power Leisure Bookmakers Limited of Waterfront, Hammersmith Embankment, London W6 9HP and the Betfair data controller is Betfair Limited of Waterfront, Hammersmith Embankment, London W6 9HP.

Paddy Power Betfair plc reserves the right to change this Policy including altering the purposes for which it processes your personal information. In the event that Paddy Power Betfair plc considers it appropriate to make any such change, the Policy will be updated and posted on our site. Your continued use of the site will constitute acceptance of those changes. The date on which the then current Privacy and Cookie Policy came into force will be as stated at the bottom of this Privacy and Cookie Policy. Please check this Privacy and Cookie Policy frequently for updates.

This Policy applies to the websites [www.paddypower.com](https://www.paddypower.com/), [www.betfair.com](https://www.betfair.com/) and associated Paddy Power and Betfair branded websites (the "Websites"), the mobile, tablet and any other Paddy Power and Betfair apps, (all of which together are referred to as the "Betting Apps"), Telephone Betting and Text Betting. Together, the Websites, the Betting Apps, Telephone Betting, Text Betting and the Additional Gaming Services (as defined in the Paddy Power Remote Gambling Terms Conditions) are referred to collectively herein as the "Services". This Policy applies to the Services referred to above as well as other services and websites not expressly referred to that are provided by Paddy Power and/or Betfair.

Any reference to the "Group" within this Policy includes Paddy Power Betfair plc and all or any of its direct or indirect subsidiary undertakings, joint venture partners, and their related companies wherever located in the world as may exist from time to time including, but not limited to, Paddy Power, Betfair, Timeform, Sportsbet and TVG. Any member of Paddy Power Betfair plc may use and share, within the group and with its advisors, the information you provide and other information it holds about you for the purposes set out below.

### _2\. CONSENT FOR DATA PROCESSING_

By providing your personal information and registering with us or logging on with us when you enter our websites, you explicitly consent to the Group processing and disclosing your Personal Information for the purposes, and otherwise in the manner set out in this Policy, or as otherwise provided in accordance with the Terms and Conditions.

### _3\. PERSONAL INFORMATION_

Personally identifiable information is any information about you and may include your name and address, date of birth, payment card details, details of betting transactions and account transfers and any other information you may wish to provide (“Personal Information”). We endeavour to ensure that our business practices that involve the use of your Personal Information are compliant with privacy regulations in all of the countries where we operate. Accordingly, in this Policy, we want not only to advise you of your privacy rights but also explain how we intend to respect them.

### 3.1 How is your Personal Information collected by our websites & what information may be collected?

Personal Information may be submitted on our websites in two areas:

**1\. Public Area**

We collect browser and cookie information when you first navigate to our Websites. We collect information about you during the account registration process for any of our Services. This information may include, but is not limited to your name, postal address, e-mail address, phone number, credit/debit card details and any other mandatory details as might be requested from you for the purpose of registration and/or continued use of our Services.

**2\. Private Area**

If you are already one of our customers and have opened an account with us, you must use a password to enter our websites.

A "session cookie" is used to enable you to leave and re-enter our Websites without re-entering your password. Our web server will record the pages you visit within our Websites.

To ensure a good quality of service, we may monitor and record any communication you have with us whether in writing (including via Live Chat), by phone or by electronic mail. We recommend that with the exception of your name and username (or “TAN” for Betfair Telephone Betting users), you do not send us Personal Information by e-mail. Any information which you transmit to us is transmitted at your own risk.

We may also collect:

(a) Entry details for competitions or promotions.  
(b) Details of your visits to our Services and the resources and webpages that you access including, without limitation, traffic data, location data and other communication data (including IP address). Note that we do not extract any personal information (e.g. email address or name) that may be in a web browser’s user preference file.  
(c) Technical information relating to the device that you use to access our Services.  
(d) Information and communications on forums on the Websites, including chat rooms and message boards.  
(e) Information we collect using cookies stored on your device about how you use our Services and/or selected third party websites - for more information on cookies please refer to Cookies section below.  
(f) Where you communicate or share information with us or other users of our Services through player forums, message boards, profile comments, in-game challenges and chat messaging with game operators or other users.  
(g) Your betting, gaming, payments and other account transactions - these are routinely analysed so as to assist us in improving the Services we provide to you.  
(h) Your telephone conversations - either to place a bet or a customer service call - these may be recorded both to assist us in training and in quality management, and to allow for the speedy resolution of queries.

It’s important to highlight that our Services are _not_ intended for individuals under the age of 18 and we do not knowingly record or retain any personal information from such individuals. In the event that we inadvertently gather personal information in relation to a minor, we will take reasonable measures to promptly close any relevant accounts and remove any records where possible, other than such information as will allow us to identify and prevent future access from such individuals

### 3.2 How your Personal Information will be used?

We will process your Personal Information in order to allow you access and make use of our Websites, to allow you to participate in the services offered, to administer your account, to maintain our accounts and records, to enable us to comply with any legal or regulatory requirements, to allow quicker account registration should you open a betting account with another company within the Group (for example, if you were to open an account with Paddy Power, we could use the verification documents submitted to Betfair to comply with our legal and regulatory requirements), to monitor website usage levels and the quality of the service we provide and to inform you, from time to time, about products and services that we consider may interest you and for related purposes.

We will also retain such information and may analyse it in order to investigate any actual or suspected criminal activity or, in respect of any event featured on our website, any threat to the integrity of that event and/or breaches of the rules of that event as laid down by the relevant governing (including sporting) bodies. All rights in the manner of recording your Personal Information held by Paddy Power Betfair plc (including copyright and database rights) are and shall remain its property.

Your information may be processed in the following ways:

(a) For general account management and processing of your transactions via your banking service provider;  
(b) For the provision of betting services;  
(c) To help identify you in case we need to interact over the phone, electronic email or any other way;  
(d) To verify your age and accuracy of your registration details, including disclosure of such information to third parties e.g. financial institutions and third party reference agencies;  
(e) To serve appropriate and tailored marketing material and content via SMS, email, phone, push notification, post or otherwise, in accordance with your marketing preferences;  
(f) To help diagnose system problems and to administer our Website;  
(g) To gather broad demographic information about you, such as determining whether you are a user from outside the UK;  
(h) To monitor and improve our Services;  
(i) To carry out customer research, testing and analysis;  
(j) To carry out risk management;  
(k) To detect and report fraud, cheating and money laundering;  
(l) To enable us to comply with any legal or regulatory requirements; and  
(m) For advertising and promotional purposes, we may publish players’ aliases and/or chat names, along with any winnings and prizes received, on the Websites.

### 3.3 To whom and where personal information may be disclosed?

Your Personal Information may, for the purposes described above, be transferred or disclosed to any company within the Group or, subject to appropriate agreement, to third parties, for the processing of that Personal Information on our behalf. The Group may, from time to time, retain trusted third parties to process your Personal Information for the purposes listed above and such processing will be governed by a contract in the form required by law.

Where required by law, your Personal Information may also be disclosed to an applicable governmental, regulatory, sporting or enforcement authority. Additionally, in circumstances where we deem it appropriate, your Personal Information may be disclosed to any regulatory authority (whether at the request of such authority or otherwise) which has issued any company within the Group with a gambling operating licence.

Your Personal Information may also be disclosed to any regulatory or sporting body in connection with policing the integrity or enforcing the rules of a sport or game and/or prevention and detection of crime and with whom the Group has agreements (Memoranda of Understanding or "MOUs") from time to time for the sharing of such data and where the Group considers that there are reasonable grounds to suspect that you may be involved in a breach of such rules or the law, have knowledge of a breach of such rules or the law or otherwise pose a threat to the integrity of the relevant sport or game. Those bodies may then use your Personal Information to investigate and act on any such breaches in accordance with their procedures.

Paddy Power Betfair plc operates businesses in multiple jurisdictions some of which are not located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”). Countries outside the EEA do not always have strong data protection laws. We will ensure that each Group company and their service providers process your information under strict contractual instruction, in a secure manner and in accordance with this Policy.

### 3.4 Accuracy and Access to Information

You are entitled and we require you to have any inaccurate information corrected so please ensure that you notify us of any updates, amendments and corrections to your information by logging into the ‘My Account’ section of your online account and amending your ‘Contact Details’ on Paddy Power and ‘My details’ on Betfair sections or by contacting our support team through one of the options available in our Help Centre. If you wish to query the nature of how we process your personal data, you can contact us at any time. Our contact details are located in the 'Contact Us' pages of our website.

You also have a right to request a copy of any personal information that we hold about you. Should you wish to make such a request you should contact us in writing at: 

Subject Access Requests c/o Legal Department, Paddy Power Betfair plc, Waterfront, Hammersmith Embankment, London W6 9HP with a cheque payment for £10 made payable to Paddy Power Betfair plc.

Or

Subject Access Requests c/o Customer Services, Paddy Power Betfair plc, Power Tower, Belfield Business Park, Clonskeagh, Dublin 4, with a cheque made payable for €6.35

You should include adequate information to identify yourself and such other relevant information that will reasonably assist us in fulfilling your request. Your request will be dealt with as soon as possible. Under the Data Protection Acts, we are entitled to charge an administration fee for processing such requests.

### 3.5 Retention and Disposal

We only keep your information for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was originally obtained. Please note that we may be required in certain circumstances to retain your information indefinitely (for example under our procedures on responsible gambling and self-exclusion). We will take all necessary steps to ensure that the privacy of information is maintained upon disposal.

### _4\. SECURITY_

We recognise that online security is an area of vital importance for all our customers. It is imperative that you should have full confidence that your personal details are secure before you register an account. We employ security measures to protect your information from access by unauthorised persons and to prevent unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage. We use state of the art technological security solutions, including encryption when transmitting sensitive information across the internet, which is certified by Thawte. This means that all personal and financial information sent to and from the Website are encrypted in accordance with good industry practice.

In order to protect both ourselves and our customers from identity theft we may verify the information you have provided with our banking institutions over secure lines. Again this is carried out in accordance with our data protection obligations.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping the password, as well as any means to manage the password such as a registered email address, secure and confidential at all times.

As the security of some communications via the internet is not completely secure, we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you disclose using your internet connection. You accept the inherent security implications of using the internet and Paddy Power Betfair plc will accept no liability for any direct, consequential, incidental, indirect, or punitive losses or damages arising out of such an occurrence.

While we follow best practice, including but not limited to implementing administrative, technical and physical measures to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft and misuse you should also take personal steps to protect the security of your data both physically and electronically by following common best practice procedures such as:

  * Running Anti-Virus software and keeping it up to date;
  * Applying operating system, web browser and other security updates;
  * Ensuring your PC or other device is not left unattended whilst logged into our Websites; and
  * Using strong passwords for all Services and logins.

### _5\. COOKIES_

The Websites (including those optimised for mobile devices) and Betting Apps use cookies and similar technologies to manage login sessions, provide personalised web pages and to tailor advertising and other content to reflect your specific needs and interests. By using the Websites and applications you agree to the use of cookies and similar technologies for the purposes we describe in this Policy.

### 5.1 Acceptance of Cookie Policy

Your use of the Services will constitute acceptance of the then current Privacy and Cookie Policy, to include any amendments thereto. Please read this policy carefully to ensure that you understand our views and practices regarding the capture, retention, processing and transfer (where applicable) of your information. If you do not agree to accept and be bound by the Privacy and Cookie Policy, please discontinue your use of the Services.

### 5.2 What is a web cookie?

Cookies are text files containing a small amount of information that are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. They are generally used by most websites to improve your online experience and to ensure that relevant content and functions are delivered and used more effectively.

Cookies perform various different functions.

For example, some cookies are downloaded to your device temporarily for the period that you browse a particular website; these cookies might allow you to navigate between pages more efficiently or enable websites to remember the preferences you select. Other cookies can be used to help websites remember you as a returning visitor or ensure the online adverts you receive are more relevant to your specific needs and interests

You can amend your browser settings to block some or all cookies. To do this, follow the instructions provided by your browser manufacturer.

However, if you block cookies from the Websites some or all the website's functions may not perform as intended.

Set out below is an indicative list of the types of cookies we use:

Cookie type | Purpose | More information  
  
---|---|---  
  
Visitor ID Cookie  
| An anonymous identifier used to recognise a visitor across visits. | It may be used to identify repeat visits and analyse cross visit behaviour.  
  
Tracking Cookie  
| An account related ID used to recognise customers and maintain your session on site. | It may be used to link site usage information with transactional information when analysing and optimising the user experience.  
  
Customisation Cookie  
| Used to customise your experience | A unique ID used to recognise you as a returning visitor and customise your experience on our Websites.  
  
Testing Cookies  
| Anonymous cookie used to randomly serve variants of content and to maintain a visitor's view of that content. | It may also be used to record a variants performance in achieving goals such as helping visitors to register.  
  
Analytics Cookies  
| These are used to collect information about how visitors use our Websites. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the Websites. | The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the Websites, where visitors have come to the Websites from and the pages they visited.   
  
Advertising Cookies  
| These are anonymous identifiers used to serve ads of third parties. | The cookies allow us to advertise to you on third party websites.  
  
You can find more information about cookies at: 

[www.cookiecentral.com](https://www.cookiecentral.com/), www.allaboutcookies.org and www.youronlinechoices.eu.

###  _6\. MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS_

As part of the initial account registration process, you are provided with an opportunity to record your marketing preferences. We endeavour at all times to respect your preferences and not send you communications in contravention of your wishes.

Where you have agreed to receive such communications, the Group or Paddy Power/Betfair (as applicable) may use your information and personal details to contact you with marketing messages by SMS, email, phone, post or otherwise. We will do this during the period of your relationship with us and, unless specifically instructed otherwise by you, for a reasonable period of time after the relationship has ended in order to inform you about products, services, promotions and special offers which we feel may be of interest to you.

These marketing messages will provide you with information about the products and services offered by any company within the Group (including, but not limited to, Paddy Power, Betfair, Timeform, Sportsbet and TVG) and information about products and services provided by our selected partners and third parties.

With your consent we may also send push notifications to your mobile device to provide game updates, communicate offers, promotions and other relevant messages. You can manage push notifications from your device's settings page for the relevant App.

You can opt out from receiving or opt in to receive such marketing communications in future by logging into your account and changing your marketing preferences within the “My Account” tab. You will also be able to opt out by following the respective unsubscribe or opt out mechanisms detailed in our electronic communications.

### _7\. EXTERNAL LINKS_

Our Websites contain links to other sites. Paddy Power Betfair plc will not be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

V 02/17 01/06/2017
